Jonathan Manas

EXPERIENCED FRONT-END DEVELOPER

jonathanmanas.dev (63) 908-8926595

Front-end developer with a strong focus on creating appealing and intuitive user interfaces (UI) and user experiences (UX). Dedicated to ensuring accessibility (a11y) across diverse user bases and platforms. I seek to join a dynamic and collaborative team to contribute my experiences in front-end development.

Experiences

Senior Front-end Developer

ConnectOS, 2023 - 2024

Outsourcing and Offshoring

- Worked with an Australian global cloud-based HSEQ Management SaaS vendor to elevate functionalities while overseeing maintenance tasks across multiple enterprise modules.
- Refactored a legacy React-based module within three months leading to its MVP launch.
- Offered technical advice as a lead developer to enhance old applications, ensuring optimal
 performance, reducing technical debts, and meeting client needs.

Senior Front-end Developer / Unit Team Lead

Code and Theory, 2018 - 2023

Digital Design Agency

- Worked on multiple US-based projects such as a retail e-commerce store, financial web app, non-profit sites, and marketing portfolios, among others under various technology stacks such as WordPress, Drupal, Salesforce, Contentful, React.
- Sustained code standards and ensured the maintainability of projects through code reviews and knowledge sharing within the front-end team.
- Provided technical and practical career support to junior developers while taking a leadership role in overseeing their work.

Front-end Developer

Citron Information Solutions, Inc., 2016 - 2018

IT Consulting

- Worked on web and desktop applications with Angular, React, and Electron.
- Managed the front-end specifications to ensure accessibility across various browsers and functionality of applications while integrating Java and PHP backends.

Senior Front-end Developer / Team Lead

Public ApS (Denmark) / RelationHouse, Inc., 2011 - 2015

Digital Advertising Agency

- Worked on multiple Danish projects such as a retail e-commerce store, an educational institution, a non-profit organization, and various HTML Emailers and Facebook campaigns.
- Handled front-end using proficient tools and standards with integrations to PHP and .Net.
- Established development guidelines to improve production workflow.
- Participated in the technical planning, task scheduling, and recruitment process
- Ensured compatibility across various browsers, addressing the diverse user base and enhancing the UX on multiple platforms.

Web Master / Graphic Artist / Marketing Head

Integrated Security and Automation, Inc., 2007 - 2010

Security Systems Provider

- Oversaw the upkeep of the company website, and its content creation.
- Led the Marketing Department in the development and execution of the company's marketing and advertising campaigns and strategies.
- Managed trade exhibitions and events, ensuring successful execution.
- Generated emailers, online newsletters, and print collaterals to support the company's promotional efforts.

Other: Resource Speaker / Trainor (ReactJS Training)

Phoenix One Knowledge Solutions, May 30 - June 01, 2018,

Tools

HTML React
CSS, Sass Next JS
JavaScript Redux / RTK
TypeScript RTK Query
Tailwind SWR

A11y React Hook Form

7ustand

WordPress

Drupal Jest / Vitest
Handlebars Cypress
React Testing Lib

Node.JS

Express JS Storybook SQL / MySQL Recharts MongoDB ChartJs

GraphQL Web Components

Git Webpack Figma

Get In Touch

Email:

jonathanmanas@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/athanph

Github:

github.com/athanph

Education

Bachelor of Science in Psychology

Far Eastern University, Manila